Nestor Narbona Chuvli

Amsterdam, NL | nestor.chulvi@gmail.com | +31 682054375 | nestor.com | linkedin/nestor github.com/nestor

Personal Statement

I am a Data Scientist based in Amsterdam. Originally from Spain, I've been living in the Netherlands for the past five years. Working with data and code is my passion, and it has been my job for a few years now. I appreciate the computational and mathematical complexities of the role, sometimes slipping into the shoes of a software developer, other times embodying a meticulous logician. I mostly enjoy working in the context of business, psychology and finance. I enjoy collaborating with colleagues and exchanging skills and different approaches to the craft.

Experience

Data Scientist, Machine Learning Programs – Amsterdam, NL

Feb 2024 – Present

- We develop pricing and risk assessment products for insurers and insurance brokers
- My role involves from the initial data analysis and exploration, to ML and modeling, and finally development of client interfaces

Teacher Assistant, University of Amsterdam - Amsterdam, NL

Jan 2023 - Feb 2024

- Teacher Assistant for Computational Sciences (BSc)
- Lectures and practical sessions on data analysis (i.e. Python) and web development (i.e. HTML, CSS, Python, SQL)
- Intake and communication with clients in development of web applications

Junior Lecturer, Athena Studies - Amsterdam, NL

May 2021 - Jun 2022

- Athena Studies is the N.1 Dutch company offering study assistance at university level
- My role involved preparing material and giving lectures on a variety of statistics and data analysis courses
- Students evaluation: 9.52

Education

University of Amsterdam, Computational Science Minor

Sept 2022 – June 2023

- GPA: 8.75/10
- Coursework: Computational modeling, data analysis, linear algebra, probability theory

University of Amsterdam, Psychology Major

Sept 2019 - June 2022

- GPA: 8.19/10 (graduated with Honors)
- Specialization: Research Methods & Statistics
- Thesis: Using Social Media Analytics to Explore Political Involvement and Polarization
- Coursework: Behavioral change, statistics, experimental design, scientific data analysis, social psychology

IES Pere Boil, Valencia, International Baccalaureate (IB)

Sept 2017 - June 2019

- GPA: 41/45
- Coursework: Business management, Spanish literature, French, mathematics, history

Projects

Modeling information diffusion in empirical and theoretical social networks

github.com/project-cs

- Evaluating empirical validity of the Barabási-Albert network model in the context of information diffusion
- Topics: Network analysis, hypothesis testing, data visualization, information diffusion modeling

^{*}Only projects not protected under NDA are shown

Stock value prediction based on sentiment analysis of financial articles

github.com/project-sda

- Evaluate the predictive value of sentiment recorded in financial news on stock prices.
- Topics: Time series, natural language processing, hypothesis testing, financial modeling

Measuring political involvement in Twitter using SVM and followers network

report

- Improvement on methods used to measure political involvement and attitude of Twitter users.
- Topics: SVM classifier, natural language processing, API, model fitting, measurement validity

Using Social Media Analytics to Explore Political Involvement and Polarization github.com/thesis-project

- Using Twitter data we evaluate the fitness of the Cusp Catastrophe model when applied to the field of attitude change.
- Topics: attitude modeling, natural language processing, API, model fitting

Technologies

Languages: Python, SQL, Bash, R, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Git, Jupyter, Pandas, Pytest, Scikitlearn, FastAPI, Flask, Seaborn, Linux, Docker, Emacs